Guide to the Civil War Stereographs 1861-1865 PR 65-1
New-York Historical Society
- Engineer corps building a road., May 24, 1864, published later (Item 810-14)
  Group of men constructing road with picks, pontoon bridge behind on river.
- Crows' nest battery and lookout, before Petersburgh, [sic] Va., [ca.1864] (Item 811-1)
  Soldiers surrounding a large artillery piece.
- Redoubt Zabriskie on Cobb's Hill to protect signal tower., [ca.1864] (Item 811-2)
  Soldiers standing and sitting around bunker.
- View showing the effect of a shell bursting though the east parlor of the Dunlop House, Petersburgh, [sic] Va., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-3)
  Interior of house showing brick rubble where a shell has shattered the wall.
- Dwelling houses on Bollingbrook St., Petersburgh, [sic] Va., showing the effect of Gen. Grant's bombardment., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-4)
  Brick houses partially destroyed, mainly on upper stories.
- Tobacco warehouse on High St. Petersburgh, [sic], Va., used by the rebels as temporary prisons. View from the south side., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-5)
  Exterior view of brick two & three story warehouse, soldiers seated on stairs.
- Tobacco warehouse on High St. Petersburgh, [sic], Va., used by the rebels as temporary prisons. Front view., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-6)
  Exterior view of brick two & three story warehouse, fence in foreground.
- Effect of the bombardment, Petersburgh, [sic], Va., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-7)
  Brick wall with large section blown out of it, tree in foreground.
- A dead rebel soldier, as he lay in the trenches of Fort Mahone, called by the soldiers "Fort Damnation.", April 2, 1865 (Item 811-8)
  Dead soldier, with rifle fallen on top of him.
- A dead Confederate soldier in the trenches at Petersburg, Va., April 2, 1865., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-9)
- A dead Confederate soldier on the Petersburg line, April 2, 1865., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-10)
  Dead soldier.
- C.S. soldier killed by a shell in the trenches of Fort Mahone, called by the soldiers "Fort Damnation.", April 2, 1865 (Item 811-11)
  Dead soldier lying in trench.
- A dead Southern soldier, as he lay on the foot passage in the trenches of Fort Mahone, called by the soldiers "Fort Damnation.", April 2, 1865 (Item 811-12)
- A dead Southern soldier, as he lay on the foot passage in the trenches of Fort Mahone, called by the soldiers "Fort Damnation.", April 2, 1865 (Item 811-13)
- C. S. soldier killed in the trenches, at the storming of Petersburg, Va. April., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-14)
  Dead soldier with bloody face lying in trench.
- C. S. soldier killed in the trenches, at the storming of Petersburg, Va. April., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-15)
- Southern soldiers, killed in the trenches of Ft. Mahone, called by the soldiers Ft. Damnation., [April 1865] (Item 811-16)
  Several dead soldiers in a deep trench, rifles lean against walls.
- Southern soldiers, killed in the trenches of Ft. Mahone, called by the soldiers Ft. Damnation., [April 1865] (Item 811-17)
- This picture is a good view of the covered ways inside the rebel Fort Mahone, called by the soldiers "Fort Damnation.", [April 1865] (Item 811-18)
  Dead soldier in trench behind a section of chevaux-de-frise.
- This picture is a good view of the covered ways inside the rebel Fort Mahone, called by the soldiers "Fort Damnation.", [April 1865] (Item 811-19)
- Confederate soldier killed in the trenches of Fort Mahone, April 1, 1865., [April 1865], published later (Item 811-20)
- A dead rebel solider, barefooted killed by a shell, which tore his side out., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-21)
- A dead rebel solider, barefooted killed by a shell, which tore his side out., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-22)
- A dead rebel solider, barefooted killed by a shell, which tore his side out, the entrails protruding from his side., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-23)
- A dead rebel soldier, inside the Union picket lines., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-24)
  Dead soldier, wall of fort in background.
- This view was taken in the trenches of the rebel Fort Mahone, called by the soldiers "Fort Damnation," the morning after the storming of Petersburgh, [sic], Va., April 2d,1865, and shows a boy about 14 years…., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-25)
  Dead boy in trench.
- This view was taken the Southern trenches, the morning after the storming of Petersburg, Va., April 2nd, 1865, and shows a dead Southern soldier who must have died instantly, his left temple and part of his head was carried away by a shell…., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-26)
  Dead soldier in trench.
- This view was taken the Southern trenches, the morning after the storming of Petersburg, Va., April 2nd, 1865, and shows a dead Southern soldier who must have died instantly, his left temple and part of his head was carried away by a shell…., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-27)
- A dead rebel soldier as he lay in the trenches before Petersburgh, [sic], Va., April 2d, 1865., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-28)
  Dead soldier in trench, his rifle by his side.
- A dead rebel soldier in the trenches before Petersburg., April 2, 1865., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-29)
- A rebel soldier, killed at the trenches before Petersburgh, [sic], the spots and marks on his face, are blood issuing from his mouth and nose., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-30)
  Dead soldier next to a pile of rubble, a building and fence are visible in the background.
- A rebel soldier, killed at the trenches before Petersburgh, [sic], the spots and marks on his face, are blood issuing from his mouth and nose., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-31)
- A rebel soldier, killed at the trenches before Petersburgh, [sic], the spots and marks on his face, are blood issuing from his mouth and nose., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-32)
- "Chevaux de frise" in front of the rebel works at Petersburgh, [sic], Va., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-33)
  Chevaux de frise laid out at all angles across an open field.
- Rebel breastworks in front of Petersburgh [sic]., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-34)
  Bunker constructed of soil and logs, soldiers stand behind it.
- Rebel breastworks in front of Petersburgh [sic]., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-35)
- Rebel breastworks in front of Petersburgh [sic]., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-36)
- Interior view of the rebel works in front of Petersburgh, [sic], Va., April 2, 1865 (Item 811-37)
  Interior view of rough fort, ammunition boxes and canteens scattered on the ground.
- View in the rear of Dunlop's house, Bollingbrook Street, Petersburgh [sic], showing ruins of tobacco warehouses destroyed by shell., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-38)
  Brick two story house with porch next to bombed brick façade of warehouse, Afro-American man in front yard of house.
- View in the rear of Dunlop's house, Bollingbrook Street, Petersburgh [sic], showing ruins of tobacco warehouses destroyed by shell., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-39)
  Two soldiers on lawn with statue, remains of brick factory is visible through trees.
- Ruins of the Petersburgh [sic] Railroad Bridge, Richmond, Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 811-40)
  Ruins of bridge showing brick pylons still standing, man walks among rubble.
- Trestle-work bridge on the Southside railroad, one mile above Petersburgh, [sic], Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 811-41)
  Trestle bridge over a river.
- Large dam on the Appomattox river, Petersburgh, [sic], Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 811-42)
  View of river showing dam, trees.
- Church built by the engineers at Poplar Grove, near Petersburgh, [sic], Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 811-43)
  Front view of wooden log church with large spire.
- Interior of the Union Fort Stedman, Petersburgh, [sic], Va., showing bombproofs., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-44)
  Interior of Fort Stedman showing bombproofs.
- Rebel encampment in front of Petersburg, 24th June, 1864., June 24, 1864 (Item 811-45)
  Encampment of log cabins and tents among trees, soldiers sitting and standing.
- Rebel encampment in front of Petersburg, 24th June, 1864., June 24, 1864 (Item 811-46)
  Encampment of log cabins, soldiers standing around buildings.
- View of rebel works in front of Petersburg, captured by the 18th Corps, under Gen. Smith, 24th June, 1864. (Item 811-47)
  View of field showing trenches and embankments, two soldiers in the distance.
- Cowan's Independent Battery, 1st N.Y., inside one of the rebel forts in front of Petersburg, 24th June, 1864., June 24, 1864 (Item 811-48)
  Interior view of fort, cannons and wagons lined up inside fence, soldiers sit under tents and stand in yard.
- Camp life in front of Peterburg during the dog days., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-49)
  View of tent with men inside, seated at table and laying in cot, horse-drawn wagon behind tent.
- View of bombproof tents occupied by U.S. colored troops in front of Petersburg, Va., August 7, 1864. (Item 811-50)
  Military camp showing bomb shelters, with soldier standing on bridge.
- Bombproof kitchen and tents on front line in front of Petersburg, August 10, 1864. (Item 811-51)
  Military camp showing camouflaged kitchen, tents, laundry, soldiers.
- A bombproof shelter for the soldiers during the seige of Petersburg, August 10, 1864. (Item 811-52)
  View of underground shelter made of earth and wood, soldiers surrounding it.
- Camp of Union soldiers on the line in front of Petersburg, Va., August 10, 1864. (Item 811-53)
  View of military camp seen through trees, showing tents, bomb shelters.
- 15-inch mortar "Dictator" in the works in front of Petersburg, view from the south., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-54)
  Wooden platform on which soldiers are gathered with large mortar, cannonballs.
- Fort Abbott, City Point line, the fort occupied by Abraham Lincoln during the fight, in front of Petersburg, that resulted in its capture., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 811-55)
  Exterior view of fort down a canal.
- Making Coffee., [ca.1864-ca.1865], published later (Item 811-56)
  Group of soldiers in a bomb shelter, another soldier heats a pot over the fire.
- The thirteen-inch mortar "Dictator.", [ca.1864-ca.1865], published later (Item 811-57)
- First wagon train entering Petersburg., [April, 1865], published later (Item 811-58)
  Wagon train entering town along road lined with houses and churches.
- Bomb-proof restaurant on the Petersburg line., [ca.1861-ca.1865], published later (Item 811-59)
  Log structure with sign, "Fruit and Oyster House," man sitting outside.
- The Union line before Petersburg., [ca.1864-ca.1865], published later (Item 811-60)
  View of earth bunker, chevaux-de-frise in front of it and wooden bomb shelters behind.
- The Union line before Petersburg., [ca.1864-ca.1865], published later (Item 811-61)
- Railroad battery before Petersburg., [ca.1864-ca.1865], published later (Item 811-62)
  Soldiers with large mortar in railroad battery car.
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-63)
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-64)
- A dead Confederate soldier., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-65)
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-66)
  Dead soldier in trench, his rifle at his right.
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-67)
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-68)
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-69)
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-70)
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-71)
  Dead soldier in trench, his rifle pointed away him.
- Dead Confederate soldier in the trenches., April 2, 1865, published later (Item 811-72)
- Old "Libby prison" building, Richmond, Va., August 23, 1863 (Item 812-1)
  Large four-story brick building, six tents in front, men standing in foreground. Maj. Thomas Turner is one of the four men in foreground.
- Jeff. Davis' Mansion, [1865] (Item 812-2)
  Three story stone house, group of men on front stairs.
- Libby Prison, [ca.1862-ca.1868] (Item 812-3)
  Four-story brick building, lower story whitewashed, small wood guardhouse at corner, several men stand outside.
- Libby Prison, [ca.1862-ca.1868] (Item 812-4)
  Four-story brick building, lower stories whitewashed, one man stands outside.
- View of Richmond, Va., ca. 1860 (Item 812-5)
  View of city from across river, showing houses, bridges, churches.
- Castle Thunder, Confederate prison., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 812-6)
  Four-story brick building seen from side, smaller wooden house next to it, two Afro-American children sit next to a pile of stones in the street.
- Richmond in ruins., [ca.1865] (Item 812-7)
  Overhead view of bombed buildings in Richmond, Virginia.
- General Lee's Residence., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 812-8)
  Front view of three-story brick house with wooden fence, surrounded by similar houses.
- The 5th Penn. Cavalry on the battle field of Oct 29th, 1864, near Richmond, Va., Oct 29, 1864 (Item 812-9)
  Cavalry gathered in center of military camp with tents and wooden shacks.
- Captured rebel guns, at the Rockets, Richmond, Va., [ca.1864-ca.1865] (Item 812-10)
  Line of small cannons, soldier standing next to them.
- The smoke stack of the rebel ram Virginia at the Rocketts, Richmond, Va., showing the effects from shot and shell, after the return from her raid down the river., [ca.1865] (Item 812-11)
  Large smoke stack on it side, riddled with holes and tears, three soldiers stand behind it.
- The capitol, Richmond, Va., [ca.1865] (Item 812-12)
  Left side and rear of large stone two-story building, seen along a tree-lined drive.
- Ruins in the burnt district, Richmond, Va., [ca.1865] (Item 812-13)
  Ruins of several brick and stone buildings or houses.
- [R. R. Depot] Richmond, Va., looking south-west, showing [?] and Gamble Hill in the distance. (Item 812-14)
  View of ruined brick buildings and rubble.
- The Petersburg Railroad depot in Richmond., [ca.1865], published later (Item 812-15)
  Locomotive missing front wheels, several soldiers stand on it, ruined buildings in background.
- Ruins of a locomotive in the Petersburg railroad depot, Richmond, Va., [ca.1865] (Item 812-16)
- The capitol, Richmond, Va., [ca.1865] (Item 812-17)
  Front view of large stone building with colonnade, men stand on porch and on ground.
- "Castle Thunder," Cary St., the place where so many Union prisoners suffered., [ca.1865] (Item 812-18)
  Side view of three-story brick building with dormers & chimneys on cobblestone street.
- Libby Prison, Richmond, Va., [ca.1865] (Item 812-19)
  Four-story brick building, lower story whitewashed, piles of coal in street.
- Ruins of the Danville Railroad bridge, Richmond, Va., [ca.1865] (Item 812-20)
  Brick pylon remains of bridge over river.
- Park of captured guns at Rocketts, Richmond, Va. (Item 812-21)
  Field full of small artillery guns, two men and dark room wagon in foreground.
- Libby Prison, Richmond, Va., [ca.1865] (Item 812-22)
  Four-story brick building, lower story whitewashed, piles of coal in street, men stand along street.
- Residence of Gen. Robert E. Lee, Richmond, Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 812-23)
  Front and side view of three-story brick house surrounded by other similar houses.
- Drupe's Bluff, near Richmond, Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 812-24)
  View of river and overlooking bluff, with pieces of artillery half-sunk in river.
- First New York Battery, 20 pound Parrot rifled guns, near Richmond, June 1862. (Item 812-25)
  Artillery in field with horses and covered wagons.
- First New York Battery, 20 pound rifled guns, near Richmond, June 1862. (Item 812-26)
  Artillery in field.
- Major Robertson's battery of horse artillery, near Richmond, June, 1862. (Item 812-27)
  Artillery and mounted soldiers in a field.
- Libbey [i.e. Libby] Prison, looking west, on Water street, Richmond., April 6, 1865 (Item 812-28)
  Four-story brick building, bottom stories whitewashed, next to other brick buildings.
- Castle Thunder, Richmond, Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865] (Item 812-29)
  Side view of three-story brick building with dormers and chimneys, small wooden guardhouse next to it.
- Libby Prison, [ca.1862-ca.1868] (Item 812-30)
  Four-story brick building, bottom stories whitewashed, men stand outside and on stairs.
- Panoramic view of Richmond in ruins., [ca.1865], published later (Item 812-31)
  Overhead view of burnt city, large brick façade of building still stands in foreground.
- Panoramic view of Richmond in ruins., [ca.1865], published later (Item 812-32)
- Panoramic view of Richmond in ruins., [ca.1865], published later (Item 812-33)
  Overhead view of burnt city, large brick façade of building still stands in foreground, river in middle ground.
- "Castle Thunder," Richmond, Va., [ca.1861-ca.1865], published later (Item 812-34)
  Three-story brick building with dormers and chimneys.
- Grave of General J. E. B. Stuart., [ca. 1865], published later (Item 812-35)
  White stone marker at gravesite at edge of trees, Hollywood cemtery, Richmond.
- A crippled locomotive in Richmond., [ca.1865], published later (Item 812-36)
- Ruins of Richmond, April, 1865., April, 1865, published later (Item 812-37)
  Ruins of railroad depot, only brick columns left standing around burned locomotive, man seated next to it.
- Ruins of Richmond, April, 1865., April, 1865, published later (Item 812-38)
- Confederate soldiers laid out for burial, on the morning of the 20th May, 1864, at Mrs. Allsop's, Pine Forest, three miles from Spottsylvania Court House, Va., May 20, 1864 (Item 813-1)
  Line of dead soldiers on ground.
- Dead Confederate soldier as he lay on the field, after the battle of the 19th May, near Mrs. Allsop's, Pine Forest, 3 miles from Spottsylvania Court House, Va., May, 1864 (Item 813-2)
  Dead soldier among logs and brush, his rifle by his side.
- 1st Mass. Heavy Artillery burying the dead at Mrs. Allsop's House, Pine Forest near Spottsylvania Court House, after the battle of 19th May, 1864. (Item 813-3)
  Soldiers digging graves, dead soldiers lie on the ground, a mounted officer oversees the activity.
- One of Ewell's Corps as he lay on the field, after the battle of the 19th May, 1864. (Item 813-4)
  Dead soldier in field with hat, canteen, rifle.
- Scene at Mrs. Allsopp's., May 20, 1864 (Item 813-5)
  Dead soldiers among pieces of wood.
- Bringing in the wounded., May 12, 1864, published later (Item 813-6)
  Soldiers with injured man on stretcher in front of wooden shed, trees.
- Confederate soldiers laid out for burial., May 20, 1864, published later (Item 813-7)
- Confederate dead on the battlefield., May 12 [19], 1864, published later (Item 813-8)
- Confederate dead on the battlefield., May 12 [19], 1864, published later (Item 813-9)
- Confederate dead on the battlefield., May 12 [19], 1864, published later (Item 813-10)
- Confederate dead on the battlefield., May 12 [19], 1864, published later (Item 813-11)
- Confederate dead on the battlefield., May 19 [20], 1864, published later (Item 813-12)
- Confederate dead on the battlefield., May 19 [20], 1864, published later (Item 813-13)
- Fort and landing at Yorktown, Va., [ca. 1861-ca. 1865] (Item 814-1)
  Port with large cannons and soldiers, ships on water in background.
- Street in Yorktown, Va., [ca. 1861-ca. 1865] (Item 814-2)
  Dirt street lined with trees and houses, two men in foreground.
- Gen'l M'Clellan's tent, Camp Winfield Scott, near Yorktown, May, 1862. (Item 814-3)
  Tent in military camp, surrounded by other tents and soldiers lounging.
- View of Yorktown and fleet from Farnhold's house with Battery no. 1, in foreground., [ca.1862] (Item 814-4)
  Battery constructed with sandbags and wooden fences overlooking river.
- Headquarters Camp Winfield Scott, near Yorktown, May 3, 1862. (Item 814-5)
  Military camp showing tents, soldiers and horses.
- Headquarters Gen'l M'Clellan, Camp Winfield Scott, near Yorktown, May 7, 1862. (Item 814-6)
  View of military camp showing tents and troops, soldiers sit on wooden fence in foreground with a horse.
- Battery no. 4, near Yorktown, mounting ten 13 inch mortars, each weighing 20,000 pounds., [ca.1862] (Item 814-7)
  View of battery along river bank showing tent, bunker, fence, and mounts for mortars.
- Battery no. 4, near Yorktown, mounting ten 13 inch mortars, each weighing 20,000 pounds., [ca.1862] (Item 814-8)
  Battery at edge of river, with wooden tent, constructed embankments, pile of cannonballs and mounts for mortars,
- Battery no. 4, near Yorktown, mounting ten 13 inch mortars, each weighing 20,000 pounds., [ca.1862] (Item 814-9)
  Seven mortars aimed over embankment, three soldiers attend them.
- Battery no. 4, near Yorktown, mounting ten 13 inch mortars, each weighing 20,000 pounds., [ca.1862] (Item 814-10)
  Seven mortars aimed over embankment, 3 soldiers attend them.
- Battery no. 4, near Yorktown, mounting ten 13 inch mortars, each weighing 20,000 pounds., [ca.1862] (Item 814-11)
  Seven mortars aimed over embankment.
- View of ravine at Yorktown., [ca.1862] (Item 814-12)
  Log buildings in ravine.
- Confederate fortifications, Yorktown, [ca.1862] (Item 814-13)
  Soldier sits on ladder behind sandbags which form a hilltop embankment.
- View of Yorktown from Cornwallis Cave, showing Confederate water batteries, with McClellan's No. 1 Battery in the distance., [ca.1862] (Item 814-14)
  Wooden houses at river's edge, with a few military tents surrounding them.
- Confederate fortifications, Yorktown., [ca.1862] (Item 814-15)
  View of cannon, cannonball and other equipment inside a fort.
- Water battery, Yorktown (Item 814-16)
  Three cannons attended by soldiers behind an embankment of sandbags overlooking river and ships.
- Exploded gun in Confederate battery, Yorktown., [ca. 1862] (Item 814-17)
  Soldiers sitting and standing around a sandbag embankment, overturned gun and debris on ground.
- Magruder battery at Yorktown., [ca. 1862] (Item 814-18)
  Four cannons at edge of fort, soldiers seated on wall.
- Confederate fortifications, Yorktown, built on the site where Cornwallis delivered up his sword., [ca. 1862] (Item 814-19)
  Fort with cannon, cannonballs and soldier overlooking river and ships.
- Naval battery, Yorktown, with Nelson church, now used as a hospital., July 1, 1862. (Item 814-20)
  Cannons pointing away from group of wooden buildings, soldier sits next to them on sandbags.
- Group, English officers, Camp Winfield Scott, near Yorktown, May, 1862. (Item 814-21)
  Group of six soldiers, four seated.
- The Siege of Yorktown, Va., 1862, published later (Item 814-22)
  Mortars behind an embankment, soldiers leaning on them, cannonballs stacked behind.
- Confederate fortifications, Yorktown, Va., [ca. 1862], published later (Item 814-23)
- View of Harper's Ferry, showing the ruin wrought by war., [ca. 1862-ca.1865] (Item 815-1)
  Two men with ruins in creek.
- View of Harper's Ferry, showing the ruin wrought by war., [ca. 1862-ca.1865] (Item 815-2)
  View of river and town showing ruins of bridge, railroad tracks, other buildings.
- John Brown's fort, Harper's Ferry from Md. Hts., [ca. 1861-ca. 1865] (Item 815-3)
  Exterior of brick building with lookout tower, two men stand next to doorway.
- Harper's Ferry, from Virginia side - looking up., 1865 (Item 815-4)
  View of town from across river showing buildings and a church.
- Harper's Ferry and R. R. bridge, from Maryland side., 1865 (Item 815-5)
  View of town and bridge from across river, showing buildings and houses.
- Harper's Ferry, from Railroad - contraband camp in foreground., 1865 (Item 815-6)
  Town view of brick buildings and homes, several tents on lot on foreground.
- Contraband camp -- Harper's Ferry, Va., 1865 (Item 815-7)
  Tents set up in a camp, a shovel and some buckets on ground, brick buildings and homes in background.